Now you know how to execute a block of code if a condition is true.
But what if you have a different block of code that you
want to execute when that condition is false?
You can use the 'else' keyword to do so.
Consider this code, which prints a message indicating
whether an integer N is even or odd.
If N is even,
this line is run.
Otherwise, this line is run.
Code indented under the 'else' is what happens when this condition evaluates to false.
The 'else' keyword is always followed by a colon and doesn't need a Boolean expression.
So, if we set N to be 4 like this,
the if statement here would evaluate to true and we would print the following string.
Alternatively, if we set N to be 15,
this condition would evaluate to false so we would skip
this block and execute the code under the else.
If you have more than two possible cases,
you can also use elif,
short for 'else if',
to deal with the situation.
This saves the multiple indentation that would be needed if
we used 'else' and then another 'if' statement inside the 'else' block.
Like 'if', an elif statement always requires a conditional expression.
For example, let's say we wanted to print what
to do with the garden based on the current season.
If we set season equal to spring, like this,
then we can see that plant the garden is
printed as its first condition evaluates to true.
Alternatively, if we set season to winter,
then each of these conditions will evaluate to false until we had
this condition which will evaluate as true and print stay indoors.
Notice here we're using double equal sign again.
Remember, a single equal sign is for assignment like we did
here when we were setting a season as a particular string.
Two equal sign is for evaluation where we are evaluating a condition as true or false.